toonboom.com 2019-11-11

# Privacy Policy

## 1\. Overview

At TOON BOOM ANIMATION Inc. (" **TOON BOOM** ", "we" or "us"), protecting your privacy is a key priority. Our goal is to treat the Personal Information you furnish us with the utmost respect, in compliance with legal requirements and in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy. " **Personal Information** " is any information about or relating to you as an identified or identifiable individual, such as your name, address, telephone number, email address, payment information and age.

By accessing, using and/or downloading materials from https://www.toonboom.com or any other websites operated by TOON BOOM (collectively, the " **Sites** "), you agree to the terms of this privacy policy (the " **Privacy Policy** ") on your own behalf and on behalf of each entity on whose behalf you act.

This Privacy Policy may be supplemented by additional privacy terms on our Sites relating to:

  1. an offering of products or services; or

  2. a request to provide your Personal Information to us.

Where inconsistent with this Privacy Policy, these more specific provisions will prevail. We encourage you to read these supplementary privacy terms in conjunction with this Privacy Policy. 

**If you have any questions or concerns about our Privacy Policy, or about our collection, use and/or disclosure of your Personal Information, please contact our privacy team at[privacy@toonboom.com](mailto:privacy@toonboom.com).**

__  
Back to Top

## 2\. What information do we collect and for what purpose?

In this section, we describe who collects visitor information on our Sites, how the information is collected, what type of information is collected, from whom the information is collected, and for what purpose.

### Cookies and similar tracking technology

Both we and certain third parties may employ cookies and related technology to track your device"s browsing activity on our Sites. A "device" in this context refers to a computer, phone, tablet or similar device that you use to access the Internet.

Cookies are small data files that we or third parties may place on your device when you visit our Sites to mark that you have been there. Cookies and related tracking technology, such as pixels or web beacons (which also utilize cookie technology), may be used to enhance and personalize the browsing experience on our Sites. For example, they allow us and third parties to track your device's browsing activity through the Sites over several sessions, including the websites your device accesses immediately before and immediately after visiting our Sites, the average time spent on our Sites, pages viewed on our Sites, and other statistics about the usage of our Sites. Through this technology, the Sites can remember the preferences associated with your device (for example, language settings) and facilitate your access to and use of the Sites (for example, keeping your session active on our Sites). We may also use information collected through this technology to monitor the performance of the Sites, for systems administration purposes, and to report visitor browsing patterns to our consultants and other third parties in aggregated form – meaning a form that does not enable any specific individual to be identified, and is thus not considered to be Personal Information.

Cookies and similar tracking technology may also be used to provide you with advertising on our Sites and on third party sites that better matches your interests and preferences, based on the record of your device"s browsing activity.

_**We want you to be able to make clear and informed decisions about the use of cookies on the Sites.**_ For more information about cookies and your options to accept, reject or limit the use of cookies on the Sites, please visit our Cookies Policy.

### Collection of Personal Information

Cookies may be used to track your device"s activity on our Sites. At times, however, we will need to collect Personal Information that is specifically about you in order to provide certain services or functions on our Sites or to fulfill your requests. This may occur, for example, when you are registering a user account on the Sites, signing up for newsletters or other communications on the Sites, or making a purchase through the Sites. In these contexts, we may need to ask you to provide, among other things, your name, mailing address, postal code, email address and phone number. When fulfilling a purchase order, we may also need to obtain payment verification information (for example, last four digits and expiry date of a credit card) and to gather additional information from third parties (including credit information) to determine your eligibility to fulfill your order. You will also need to provide full payment information to our outsourced payment processor to complete an online purchase. We do not receive your payment information for online purchases other than the limited verification details described above.

The Personal Information that you provide to us in these contexts will be used to provide you with products or services you have requested, to service your account, to improve our services, to respond to your questions and concerns, and other reasonable purposes identified at the time of collection.

As part of our commitment to transparency, when collecting Personal Information, we will:

  1. always indicate the specific, explicit and legitimate purpose for collection;

  2. only collect Personal Information that is reasonably necessary to fulfill this purpose or these purposes;

  3. not use the Personal Information for purposes other than those disclosed at the time of collection, except as permitted by law;

  4. disclose the categories of third parties that may receive the Personal Information; and

  5. take every reasonable step to ensure that the Personal Information is accurate, having regard to the purpose(s) for which it was collected.

**If at any time you have questions about a request on our Sites to collect Personal Information, please contact our privacy team at[privacy@toonboom.com](mailto:privacy@toonboom.com).**

### Web server log information

Our Sites" server, which is located in Canada, automatically logs the temporary or permanent address of the device that you use to access our Sites (known as an " **IP Address"** ) as well as other information about your visit such as the pages accessed, browser type, information requested, the date and time of the request, the source of your access to our Site (e.g. the website or URL (link) which referred you to our Site), and your browser version and operating system. We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the Sites, for IT security purposes, and to improve the function of our Sites.

### Minors

Our Sites are directed towards adult visitors, being individuals who have reached the age of majority in the jurisdiction from which he or she accesses our Sites. No portion of our Sites is directed towards individuals that have not reached the age of majority in the jurisdiction from which he or she accesses our Sites (" **Minors** "), nor should Minors visit our Sites without supervision from a parent or legal guardian.

We do not knowingly collect, use or disclose information from individuals under the age of 16. If you believe an individual under the age of 16 who is under your responsibility (as a parent or legal guardian) has provided Personal Information to our Sites, please contact Toon Boom"s Privacy Team at [privacy@toonboom.com](mailto:privacy@toonboom.com) and we will delete it. Parents and legal guardians are requested to review this Privacy Policy and discuss its main features with their children, in a manner that the child will understand.

__  
Back to Top

## 3\. Communication of your information to third parties

In this section, we will describe the limited circumstances in which we may disclose your information to third parties.

### Disclosure of your Personal Information to service providers

We use a number of third parties to provide us with services which are necessary to run our business. Examples include email providers, hosting providers and payment processors. These services are often provided by service providers based in Canada, which the European Commission has determined to be adequate as a privacy regulatory environment. We also work with service providers based in the United States that have self-certified compliance with the EU-US Privacy Shield.

Your Personal Information will be shared with these service providers where necessary in response to your requests, including accessing our Sites, registering a user account on our Sites, or ordering goods and services on our Sites. We require our service providers to use and, where necessary, disclose Personal Information only in accordance with the purposes for which the information was collected.

When collecting Personal Information, we will disclose the categories of third parties that may receive your Personal Information. We do not display the identities of our service providers publicly by name for security and competitive reasons. If you would like further information about the identities of our service providers, please contact us at [privacy@toonboom.com](mailto:privacy@toonboom.com) and we will provide you with such information where you have a legitimate reason for requesting it (where we have shared your information with such service providers, for example).

### Disclosure of aggregated data to third parties

We may aggregate statistics that we gather about our customers, sales, website traffic patterns, and products and services. This aggregated data is not considered Personal Information, as it does not provide information about an identifiable individual. We may disclose these statistics to third parties for a variety of purposes including management of the Sites, business optimization and market research.

### Disclosure of your information for legal reasons

In certain circumstances, it may be necessary for us to disclose your Personal Information to comply with legal obligations or to assert legal rights, as set out below. In all cases, we will limit the disclosure to the degree reasonably necessary to satisfy the obligation or assert the right.

We may, for example, be required to disclose your Personal Information to a governmental, regulatory, law enforcement or judicial body pursuant to a court order, warrant, subpoena, or similar process. We may also disclose your Personal Information to an appropriate authority if we or such authority suspects that criminal or potential criminal conduct has occurred. This could be the case, for instance, if we suspect that fraud or a cyber crime has been committed or if we or a third party has received threatening or malicious communication. We will generally only need to disclose your Personal Information for this purpose if you were involved or affected by such an incident.

We may disclose your Personal Information in connection with exercising our legal rights including, for example, sharing information with debt collection agencies if you do not pay amounts owed to us when you are contractually obliged to do so. Our legal rights may be contractual (where we have entered into a contract with you) or non-contractual (such as legal rights that we have under copyright law or tort law).

We may need to disclose your Personal Information if we are involved in a dispute with you or a third party. For example, it may be necessary to disclose your Personal Information to resolve a dispute or as part of any action related to indemnification, mediation, arbitration or court resolution or similar process.

### Disclosure of your information as part of a major business transaction

We may share your information with an actual or prospective purchaser or seller in the context of a business or asset sale or acquisition by us, a merger or a similar business combination event, whether actual or potential.

__  
Back to Top

## 4\. How do you access, update or delete your information?

Subject to the limitations set out below, on request from you we will:

  1. inform you of what Personal Information we are storing and using about you, the purposes for which we are storing and using such Personal Information, and related information as specified by law;

  2. make any corrections to such Personal Information; and/or

  3. delete such Personal Information from our systems, except where provided by law.

There are several circumstances in which we may not be able to process some or all of the above requests:

  1. we are unable to verify your identity – for example, you are unable to provide us information that proves your identity to us;

  2. fulfilling the request would reveal the Personal Information of a third party; or

  3. fulfilling the request would impose undue burden or expense on us.

If we receive a request to delete Personal Information that was collected from a location within the European Union or Switzerland, we will take reasonable steps, taking account of the available technology and the cost of implementation, to inform any third parties that have received your Personal Information from us that you have requested the erasure of any links to, or copy or replication of, your Personal Information.

In order to access, correct or delete your Personal Information, please contact us by email at [privacy@toonboom.com](mailto:privacy@toonboom.com).

__  
Back to Top

## 5\. How is your information secured and protected?

We use encryption and/or authentication tools, among other methods, to protect the transmission of Personal Information. Please note, however, that emails you send to us are not necessarily secure when they are transmitted to us.

Certain sections of our Sites allow you to order products and services, for which you may be required to provide your credit card information. These sections use Transport Layer Security (TLS) protocol for browsers that support 256-bit encryption. TLS encrypts information to ensure that it travels securely between the customer and TOON BOOM. You will know that your browser is secure by a change in the URL from "http://" to "https://". If the URL on a page asking you to provide information remains as "http://", beware as this may result in an unsecure transmission. If you are not using a browser which adheres to the TLS protocol and supports 256-bit encryption, the information you provide may not be secure and we recommend that you contact us by telephone at +1-514-278-8666 to place your order.

When processing credit card purchases over the Internet, our third party payment processor will verify your credit card information with the appropriate financial institution prior to processing your purchase. Your interactions with this third party service provider are governed by the privacy policy of such third party"s website. Neither we nor our third party service provider will supply your credit card information to any other third party.

We instruct our employees with access to your Personal Information that it is to be used only in adherence with the principles set forth in this Privacy Policy and the laws applicable to each specific business. Employees who misuse Personal Information will be subject to disciplinary measures or legal action by Toon Boom.

__  
Back to Top

## 6\. How long do we retain your information?

Whether server log information, order information or correspondence, we only hold your information for the length of time needed to fulfill the purpose for which it was submitted, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law.

__  
Back to Top

## 7\. What if we change our Privacy Policy?

TOON BOOM reserves the right to modify or supplement this Privacy Policy at any time. If we make any material change to this Privacy Policy, we will post a notice on our home page with a link to the updated Privacy Policy. Please read any such notice and the new policy statement.

Your continued use of the Sites after we post such notice will constitute your acceptance of the new terms and their application to your use of the Sites and the information disclosed for such use, including information previously furnished to us, as if they were the initial terms. However, we will seek your consent if we want to use your Personal Information for purposes other than those you have agreed to previously.

__  
Back to Top

## 8\. Third party website links

The Sites may contain links to third party sites, including those of our business partners, vendors and advertisers. While we try to link only to sites that share our high standards and respect for privacy, please understand that we are not responsible for the content or the privacy practices employed by other sites. _**Please be sure to review the privacy policies of any third party sites that you visit from the Sites.**_

__  
Back to Top

## 9\. Surveys and contests

From time to time, we may conduct online surveys to better understand the needs, characteristics, and experience of our visitors. Participation in these surveys is voluntary. Some online surveys may ask you for Personal Information, such as an email address, in addition to requesting answers to survey questions. Once you provide us with such information about yourself, your browsing on this Site will no longer be anonymous to us. We may make the results of any survey publicly available, although we will not identify you or attribute any particular response to you without your explicit consent.

On occasion, we may make contests available to qualifying users of the Sites. Participation is always voluntary and subject to the applicable contest rules. The contest may ask you to provide Personal Information as a condition of participation. We may make the names of contest winners public, as provided in the rules of each contest, or as required by applicable law.

__  
Back to Top

## 10\. Posted information, bulletin boards and discussion areas

Certain portions of the Sites allow you to post or publicly disclose information such as your CV, news, animations or other material (" **Posted Information** "). Please be aware that any Posted Information becomes public and that such Posted Information will not be protected by this Privacy Policy. You should therefore exercise caution when deciding to submit information to become Posted Information. You should also be aware that if you voluntarily disclose Personal Information as Posted Information, including on the bulletin boards or in the discussion areas of the Sites, that Posted Information may be collected and used by others and may result in unsolicited messages from other people over which we have no control.

__  
Back to Top

## 11\. Providing and withdrawing consent to commercial messages

With your opt-in consent, we may send you messages (by e-mail, for example) from time to time informing you of additional products or services provided by TOON BOOM, our affiliates or our business partners that may be of interest, or answering questions you may have. Your consent to these messages may be withdrawn at any time by clicking the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of each of these messages, or by contacting us at [privacy@toonboom.com](mailto:privacy@toonboom.com).

You are able to unsubscribe from Toon Boom Animation correspondence at any time. To manage your subscriptions, go to: https://account.toonboom.com/profile/edit and deselect the "Stay in Touch" option. An alternative way to instantly unsubscribe is to follow the direct link "Unsubscribe" at the top of any one of our emails.

__  
Back to Top

## 12\. We want your feedback

In order to continually monitor and strengthen our privacy procedure, we have on staff a Manager of Privacy, who can be contacted at [privacy@toonboom.com](mailto:privacy@toonboom.com). Please contact our webmaster if you have questions about information security, privacy and usage at [webmaster@toonboom.com](mailto:webmaster@toonboom.com) that were not answered here.

We welcome any suggestions to our Privacy Policy by email at [privacy@toonboom.com](mailto:privacy@toonboom.com) or by mail at:

> **Toon Boom Animation Inc.**  
>  4200 St-Laurent Blvd, Suite 1020  
>  Montreal, Quebec, Canada  
>  H2W 2R2 

Please make any communications as complete and descriptive as possible, and we will attempt to respond promptly to your concerns.

__  
Back to Top
